“What would the world be like if there were no hunger?”
“如果没有饥饿，世界会是什么样子？”
It’s a question that Professor Crystal would ask her students.
这是克丽斯特尔教授常会问学生的一个问题。
They found it hard to answer, she wrote later, because imagining something that isn’t part of real life—and learning how to make it real—is a rare skill.
她后来写道，学生们觉得这个问题很难回答，因为想象现实生活中并不存在的事物，并学会如何把它变成现实，是一种难得的本领。
It is taught to artists and engineers, but much less often to scientists.
艺术家和工程师会接受这种本领的训练，而科学家接受这种训练的机会则少得多。
Crystal set out to change that, and helped to create a global movement.
克丽斯特尔着手改变这一状况，并帮助发起了一场全球性运动。
The result—an approach known as systems thinking—is now seen as essential in meeting global challenges.
其成果是一种名为“系统思维”的方法，如今被视为应对全球性挑战必不可少的手段。
Systems thinking is crucial to achieving targets such as zero hunger and better nutrition because it requires considering the way in which food is produced, processed, delivered and consumed, and looking at how those things intersect with human health, the environment, economics and society.
系统思维对于实现“零饥饿”和“改善营养”等目标至关重要，因为它要求考虑食物生产、加工、运送和消费的方式，并审视这些环节如何与人类健康、环境、经济和社会相互交叉。
According to systems thinking, changing the food system—or any other network—requires three things to happen.
按照系统思维，要改变食物系统或其他任何网络，需要做到三件事。
First, researchers need to identify all the players in that system; second, they must work out how the players relate to each other; and third, they need to understand and quantify the impact of those relationships on each other and on those outside the system.
第一，研究人员需要找出该系统中的所有参与者；第二，他们必须弄清这些参与者彼此之间有何关联；第三，他们需要理解并量化这些关系对彼此以及对系统外各方的影响。
Take nutrition.
以营养为例。
In the latest UN report on global food security, the number of undernourished people in the world has been rising, despite great advances in nutrition science.
根据联合国最新发布的全球粮食安全报告，尽管营养科学取得了巨大进步，世界上营养不良的人数却一直在上升。
Tracking of 150 biochemicals in food has been important in revealing the relationships between calories, sugar, fat and the occurrence of common diseases.
追踪食物中的150种生化物质，对于揭示热量、糖、脂肪与常见疾病发生之间的关系一直很重要。
But using machine learning and artificial intelligence, some scientists propose that human diets consist of at least 26,000 biochemicals—and that the vast majority are not known.
但一些科学家借助机器学习和人工智能提出，人类饮食由至少26000种生化物质构成，而且其中绝大多数尚不为人知。
This shows that we have some way to travel before achieving the first objective of systems thinking—which, in this example, is to identify more constituent parts of the nutrition system.
这表明，要实现系统思维的第一个目标，我们还有一段路要走；在这个例子中，这一目标就是找出营养系统中更多的组成部分。
A systems approach to creating change is also built on the assumption that everyone in the system has equal power.
推动变革的系统方法还建立在这样一个假设之上：系统中的每个人都拥有平等的权力。
But as some researchers find, the food system is not an equal one.
但正如一些研究人员发现的那样，食物系统并不平等。
A good way to redress such power imbalance is for more universities to do what Crystal did and teach students how to think using a systems approach.
要纠正这种权力失衡，一个好办法是让更多大学效仿克丽斯特尔的做法，教学生如何运用系统方法进行思考。
More researchers, policymakers and representatives from the food industry must learn to look beyond their direct lines of responsibility and adopt a systems approach.
更多研究人员、政策制定者和食品行业的代表必须学会把目光投向自身直接职责范围之外，并采用系统方法。
Crystal knew that visions alone don’t produce results, but concluded that “we’ll never produce results that we can’t envision”.
克丽斯特尔明白，仅有愿景并不能带来成果，但她得出的结论是：“我们永远无法取得自己无法想象的成果。”